my is that time again for another
amazing raw recipe Food demo better late
than never I hope you all feel the same
way excited to be inviting Emma Raymond
on we're making a recipe from her seven
day raw reset it's going to be really
darn good tantalizing Thai Pad Thai I'm
really darn excited for it we got raw
vegan m in the house already and we'll
invite her in and get right
I got a little bit behind with some of
this stuff going on behind the scenes
but this will be really delicious and
and just so you guys know we're around
that 40 hour mark right near there hey
how's it going Emma hey how are you I'm
doing good awesome I'm doing pretty darn
good a little bit uh uh ill-prepared but
decent I'm doing pretty good there you
go yeah you've been out yeah you've got
a busy week with the raw vegan bundle I
bet
it's been a little bit crazy I'll admit
you know and there's been a couple
wrenches Instagram has been acting up
and randomly logging me out today and
doing some weird things but uh we
persist we move on and we just do the
best we can that's it's amazing that's
amazing yeah you're very resilient
that's great
what's going on over there yeah pretty
crazy with the raw vegan bundle but it's
been lots of fun making all sorts of new
recipes had the best food of my life
this week so it's been fun do you have
do you have a favorite you've made so
far oh I don't even know there's been so
many good ones um obviously the wraps um
by like the Highlight those were very
unique something I never done before I
mean lots of great desserts as well I
made some raw vegan brownies and cakes
and stuff so that's always fun I have a
big Sweet Tooth but tomorrow I'm making
some raw vegan brownie cakes so I'm
pretty darn excited for that that'll be
really darn good ah that would be
amazing yeah any favors that you've made
so far
probably similar you know the wrap was
ridiculous
um the cookies oh my gosh it made some
durian cookies from raw Chef Ian those
were really darn good uh the king of
kale chips they were legitimately the
best kale chips I've ever had
um I'm excited for this Thai Dish
because I I love tantalizing Thai it
tantalizes me every time
there you go there you go so I'm I'm
really stoked for that but I'm excited
to get into even more because
some that I intended to make got a
little bit left behind because of how
busy it got and some technical stuff but
uh I'm excited because the good thing is
once you got the bundle you got the
bundle and you can utilize it throughout
the rest of the year right so and um
might as well mention that really quick
you can get the bundle in either of our
links and if you're not already
following Robbie and Emma you can click
her here and make sure you do and grab
the bundle through her we have about 40
hours left that's really about it and
then this is gone for an entire other
year and even when there's another one
next year sometime maybe
it's gonna be completely different you
know so this is a completely unique
bundle everything brand new launched
right in it and I know it will block
will blow your guys's socks off so yeah
absolutely yeah that's definitely check
it out it has
that's great absolutely so I'm curious
with your book The Seven Day raw reset
what what was your motivator to create
this besides just a bundle yeah
so I got a lot of requests for people
that were looking to transition into raw
foods that needed like they wanted a set
meal plan just because it's really
confusing right getting into this raw
food it's kind of a unique concept and
in the in the mainstream world is kind
of unheard of to eat just you know raw
foods and to get all your nutrition from
raw foods and so people were really
concerned and they're like I want a meal
plan and so I finally gave gave people
they wanted gave them a meal plan that
you know combined you know all these
different recipes that I loved and um
felt what were really Health promoting
right they were low fat they were high
in fruits and vegetables they helped you
can help you with weight loss weight
gain whatever you whatever you need they
can kind of help solve those health
issues and it's a really easy way to
start out if you're looking to eat
healthier but need something super
simple and super easy awesome I love it
well it's very beautifully made and a
lot of the recipes look really dang good
and this one jumped out to me but
there's a bunch of other ones I just had
Thai on my mind and I love noodles so
I'm really darn excited for this I'll
admit I have one wrench that may be
thrown into our mix but we'll see what
happens when we get there yeah that's
the fun thing about raw foods is it's
the whole experiment and you know
honestly it's kind of hard to mess up
because as long as you got the good
flavors you can kind of add your own
spin on it right yeah absolutely
absolutely so I have everything back
here
what do you say do you shall I just read
off ingredients and put them in or do
you have an idea of how you'd like this
to flow yeah read it off yeah let's test
people out yeah you guys are watching
to hop on try this recipe let's see so
here we go I got a big nice glass bowl
it's empty we want to fill this up so
we're going to start with one zucchini
spiralized and I didn't have a
spiralizer I just had a julienne peeler
but so I got some nice long kind of uh
straight zucchini noodles ah absolutely
I get to get the zoodles yeah perfect I
love them are you a zoodle girl or are
you a coodle girl I'm a zoodle girl
cucumber noodles
for zucchini they're a little bit uh a
little bit better in my opinion but I'll
admit I'm more of a zoodle man myself I
I like a coodle but a zoodle
and I actually coined the word Napa
doodle
because of the Napa cabbage noodle where
you like slice napa cabbage real thin
like noodles I like those too and
zoodles and Napa Doodles with some
coodles
that's that's great yeah we got some Dr
Seuss living here I love it yeah I mean
we have a little bit of that energy
going on I love it so I got that
um I have one carrot that I actually
grated but I mean it says to uh julienne
yeah a perfect yeah those of you
watching they're making no cucumbers or
zucchinis or carrots really just make
them bite size make it make it easy to
eat on yeah whether that's you know
julienning it couldn't really spin
getting the spiralizer whatever makes it
easiest to get to get in the mouth
absolutely get it right into the Milky
part yeah awesome all right so we got
that we got one half of a red bell
pepper that I did manage to julienne so
we go
kind of Matchstick Julian a little bit
it's funny like the all the fancy words
I was recently uh told about like the
difference between like a smidge and a
a dash and a oh where was the other one
there's all these fancy words and they
actually like you know in my mind like a
dash and a smidge thought like oh yes
just a little bit but they have like
exact measurements for each one of those
so wild that's wild yeah who knew who
knew 16th of a teaspoon you know it was
like a dad I'm not I don't remember
which one is which I'm gonna need to
look it up but I was kind of like wow
that's kind of crazy wow so that is
crazy yeah who knew
one cup of shredded red cabbage perfect
this is already looking and sounding
good because we just got the rainbow
started here yeah absolutely get all the
rainbows in everyone that's watching
yeah lots of lots of different colors
and again yeah anyone that's watching if
you don't like any of these vegetables
just you know omit them right it'll
still be great
for say cabbage person just just leave
out the Cabbage maybe add some more
carrot in there you know vice versa
so if you don't like cabbage you don't
have to just like go directly home no do
not Pasco and and Fry and not eat yeah
yeah
seriously yeah yikes yikes all right so
we got that and then the last one in
here I got a hefty cup of edamame there
you go yeah something something just
about that word edamame you know it's
like
fun to say kind of like uh Umami you
know I don't know which one's funnier
um
those are both fun words I love all the
Asian words yeah edamame edamame is
amazing
there you go
it looks delicious I'll have to go make
some of this after oh
I'm excited all right so this is the
little bit of the wrench
it's kind of two wrenches a little bit
but I um did not have coconut aminos I
somehow missed that but what I have to
substitute is some olives yeah
um yeah absolutely
the other thing is it says to whisk
ingredients
but I'm in an apartment without a whisk
and this is the this is the real
potential wrench this new Vitamix
doesn't do a great job blending less
than like a cup and a half
but I already have the what did I have
um a fourth a cup or about 57 grams of
almond butter in there
and I put a little bit of extra water in
there so it may be a little bit thinner
just what makes it worse of course and
so we have that uh fourth a cup of
almond butter we have I probably have
about a quarter cup of water we have the
equivalent ish of one tablespoon of
coconut aminos but instead it's the
olives
we have one date
and we have two tablespoons of lemon or
lime juice right yeah
that's perfect just
giving her in here I'm pretty I was
pretty sure these lines were about
tablespoon per half yeah
absolutely this is a great way for those
of you watching this is a great way to
show kind of how you can make it your
own and if you don't have coconut aminos
use something else that gives it a
little bit of that salty kind of Asian
flavor so olives work great maybe like a
low sodium soy sauce can work too and
yeah just really you know go with the
flow and that's the fun thing about raw
foods is it's all about you know what
flavors you like so if you personally
don't like a certain flavor then maybe
you know mix it up try something else if
you're not an almond butter person
dressing peanut butter you know or
something something kind of similar
right mix it up right
it I'm sorry my cat tried to jump on the
table oh I just realized that I'm not
even showing anything here I'm gonna I'm
gonna bring the camera down a little bit
and hopefully it doesn't oh my gosh
don't do that oh my
there we go oh there we go okay proper
perfect perfect my cat snood or tried to
jump on here but she jumped directly
into the green onions which
she didn't like that's not because
that's not good at all oh we got a
question here
um it says is the edamame steamed or
Ross you want to talk a little bit about
how you uh how you when it comes to like
frozen peas or frozen edamame how do you
eat that best so whether it's edamame
although edamame
had it straight from the pod
totally Raw
I don't remember to be honest with
frozen peas in general if they're from a
bag from the grocery store they're going
to be flash uh flat pasteurized and then
Frozen so it's a light cooking but
generally doesn't cook all the way
through yeah and for myself I I prefer
to get fresh peas and then reason myself
but I don't really sweat at having
frozen peas on occasion because I don't
notice any difference in terms of
digestion or how they make me feel if I
have them either way except had fresh
ones Frozen myself and ones from the
store and eating the exact same meal at
the same amounts and I'm not a raw food
to be a raw foodist I'm a raw foodist to
feel happy and healthy and connected to
eating foods that feel great to me and
just so happens that 99 of that is all
raw foods but sometimes some frozen peas
or some edamame which they were frozen
in there and it's kind of funny I
actually yesterday bought some edamame
and I just found the the organic ones
they had in the store and brought them
home and then 10 15 more see 30 minutes
ago I started thawing them but when I
opened the bag I realized hey these are
the whole edamame pods you know I was
like this is going to be painstaking
opening up every single one when I'm
already a little bit tardy so so luckily
I looked and because I'm renting a place
here uh the fellow who owns a place he
had another box of edamame in the bottom
so I broke that open thought that out
and here we have this so they would have
been I don't know for sure if they would
have been steamed or Flash pasteurized
but um do you know on that one yeah I'm
not quite sure on edamame honestly you
said it best where it's when it comes to
how they process foods when you're
buying it frozen I'm not really sure the
process I know that they don't fully
cook it I know that they usually will
just get really quickly like you know
it's usually less than an hour no it's
usually less than a minute yeah yeah
and so yeah so it's I'm not really sure
what the process is but you're right you
said it best I'm not I'm not in it to be
a perfectionist I'm in it to feel my
best to feel energy to feel vitality and
I feel I feel perfectly fine you know
defrosting some some frozen veggies just
you know laying them out in the sun
getting them up to room temperature
um if you're in a pickle guys you can
always get some warm water and kind of
let those soak in the warm water too
right that thing you do right but yeah
you can I got another question yet you
can eat edamame raw same with peas right
that food that food is not gonna hurt
you raw at all
um you can't sit on them you know you
could just sit on them to warm them up
like a mother you go whatever you want
to do yeah
I was okay one clove of garlic
what do you think do I go for a big one
or a medium one
how do you like your garlic are you a
garlic fan Chris yup this year I've only
eaten eaten close this will be my second
close but but I um there are periods of
time where like I went to I think the
longest like probably five years ago
garlic and then I've had periods of time
where I have it at least a few times a
month and even maybe every other day and
sometimes too sometimes a lot of garlic
more often I use dry garlic powdered
garlic
um but I I do enjoy it from time to time
and especially when it's in traditional
dishes where it's like it's really
intrical it's like I want this to be
authentic you know and and I enjoy the
flavor plus there is some really helpful
beneficial uh fibers in there you know
some Prebiotic fibers that are nice in
the garlics do you like that yeah I do
vampire garlic yeah kind of like you I
will go through faces where I'll eat a
lot of garlic and then phases where Hong
Kong go without it but yeah especially
when it's integrated into a recipe
especially Asian dishes I can be a
sucker for some good garlic yeah yeah
absolutely absolutely so I think what
I'm gonna do with this though quickly is
I'm going to try and blend the sauce
without it and see how it goes because
it may require a little more blending
than I would have liked and sometimes
garlic can get bitter if you over blend
so depending how that goes I'll either
throw it in once it's partially Blended
or I'll dice it up and just add it in
perfect yeah sounds great sounds great
all right so let's get this in Poland
ski see how it goes
um
see I'll do a little vacuuming thing I
got this trusty bioshack vacuum top that
magically fits right on top of the
Vitamix and
creates a little bit of a vacuum blender
action
perfect yeah
so let's see we'll get it started this
party started
oh yeah
flip
sorry I had my uh sesame seeds on this
plate and the Vitamix fan included
oh no oh all across the table this is so
highly embarrassing I'm so sorry
no that's great it's it's authentic life
guys that that happens sometimes they're
they're kitchen kitchen accidents and we
just we just embrace it guys we just
embrace it absolutely at least it wasn't
one of those ones where the top was off
have you ever had the experience where
you turn your blender on full blast with
the top up and it goes whoosh oh yeah
many times many times
that's that's the best
oh that's nice that's actually quite
nice okay so
wow that's actually let's just see yeah
well that Blended really well so we have
that
um I have the garlic I'm just gonna give
it a quick little rough half chop and
then throw it in there
and
then
let's see
we have for toppings some green onions
and uh cilantro and sesame
so I'll just pulse this one real quick
laughs
foreign
so with the cilantro what do you think
should I should I I should have probably
uh finally chopped that action hey yeah
it depends how you like to eat it if you
don't mind big chunks of cilantro then
you just throw it in there
yeah I do love cilantro I tell you but
you know what
I will
I will do a quick little little Chopper
rooski
and hopefully I will not uh you ever
seen the movie UHF no what's that
so it's pretty funny it's a movie with
um Weird Al Yankovic okay okay as well
as uh the guy who played Kramer from
Seinfeld
wow that's 40 got canceled and
um long before this is like an older
movie this is probably from early 90s
Maybe
and
it's really funny the only reason I
brought it up though is there was a
scene with a guy doing a cooking
demoni's chopping and then all of a
sudden he's like boom G and you like cut
off a full finger oh no squirting all
over he's like oh and he's like
squirting it all over it it's kind of a
jackass comedy but um yeah yeah I I want
to prevent that and uh that's not good
yeah
uh everyone that's watching it let us
know
I'll try this pad thai at home because
this is looking amazing it's making me
hungry I definitely will have to go make
this later and
Chris is doing a great job showing us
how
I'm really banging excited to eat I'm
I'm a hungry boy I tell you to be honest
so let's see we have the sauce we have
those that we can uh add the green
onions on after I'm going to do the
unthinkable and grab a spatula which I
do not have on hand
and let's see
so what do you think does it look a
little bit funny because of the the
dates or is it or not the dates the
olives look good it looks good I mean
yeah I think I think it's great to show
the Alternatives you know if I'm ever
running out of coconut aminas I'll have
to try it with the olives because it
gives it that same kind of little salty
salty Umami flavor absolutely
absolutely all right there we go so I'm
gonna get this end
give this a pour on
oh my that might have been a garlic
chunk oh my my that's all right
there we go I'm gonna scoop a little
extra in here
from there
perfect yeah
get your Asian flavors going yeah Pad
Thai is really great for those of you
that aren't aren't big salad people
definitely try some pad thighs or some
raw vegan pasta some pesto there's lots
of mixed recipes
um yeah Chris also has an amazing you
want to talk a little bit about what
your recipe book is you created an
amazing book that I I personally love
thank you sure yeah my um my book is
called Cravings Busters sweet and savory
stews and it's a mix of classic really
uh popular stews from around the world
made raw vegan and
um for example I have actually a Thai
curry that I made yesterday which is
more kind of I mean it's a curry-ish
stew and then the tomorrow night I'll be
making uh Ethiopian lentil watt which is
a kind of like a cabbage Curry using a
very traditional
Ethiopian spice called braver which is
one of my all-time favorite spices ever
um and there's a whole bunch of
different ones ranging from uh kind of
like a minestrone kind of stew to a
Jamaican jerk's dude or not jerks dudes
Jamaicans do and a whole bunch of
different ones but um
they're tasty and fun and really hearty
and I utilize a couple different tips
and tricks to get different textures and
try and really make them seem kind of
cooked feeling and tasting but you know
easier on digestion and you know there
are lots of fun there's definitely a fun
creative process to make those ones and
hopefully a lot of people enjoy them as
well
so I'm curious for those who don't know
you how did you get into health and raw
foods
health problems and it was me trying to
like figure out that so I did kind of
what most people do is they do the whole
dieting
um you know bouncing between keto and
Mediterranean paleo and really what that
came down to was just calorie
restriction and so you got into that
very fun Loop of uh starving yourself
and then being and not repeating the
response and so I quickly found the uh
plant-based oh that's looking amazing
wow look at that this is going to be
ridiculously good I can already tell
nice the flavors and things are mingling
perfectly there you go there you go if
you did get a fun comment of uh they're
asking you how are you eat your zoodles
with a spoon since you frown upon Forks
oh the frown upon Forks has carried over
from last talks I am allergic to Forks
um I I've been known to eat like things
that are absurd with spoons with spoons
just to continue my spoon eating
I think this year maybe used a fork a
couple times you know like it's you know
I don't carry my spoon with me but I
could and I maybe should no I won't
shoot myself about that but I I mean
it's pretty easy I mean you just go like
that and like I just get my mouth close
to the bowl and just kind of like
oh there you go
uh I think there's two people in this
world spoon people and Fork people and
I'm team spoon me too I'm team spoon or
hand sometimes yeah but if I can't use a
spoon then I'm just I'm getting in their
fingers you know that's what they're
making it for right
these are just the forks right these are
the the forks of the world right yeah
exactly yeah those Forks were just
designed for people who thought they
didn't they were above having their four
cans using things you know
oh
oh you're watching I just was you know
sick of that kind of yo-yo dieting and
so I got into plant-based and I felt
really good and then I kind of stumbled
upon raw food and it was actually
finding people like Chris and Liza from
those kind of people and I found the
money social media and I just was you
know Blown Away with how healthy they
were
um and I just started trying it and it
worked amazing and I healed everything I
now find Total Health and vitality and
everything so
that's so awesome yeah you guys you guys
have been life-changing absolutely so oh
so so great blessed blessed to to have
an impact uh in any way and also you're
a part of the bundle and sharing that
out right because we're all inspired by
somebody and groups of people and and
then we bring it in and then we share it
out and it's just an expansion right
it's always coming in and out and
Rippling out and it's a something the
world really needs you know absolutely
especially you Chris I mean I know
there's a lot of there's a lot of you
know female rock people but to see see a
guy that's still big and strong and
healthy and you know amazing but living
off of fruits and vegetables that's a
huge Testament I've definitely been
showing a lot of a lot of the gym Bros a
lot of the guys how healthy they can be
on raw foods
well I appreciate that you know it's
funny I actually feel pretty thin right
now it's wild I was talking with other
creators and some other creators while
they're making their books you know
they're testing a whole bunch and and
they actually gained a little bit of
weight I I managed to lose weight uh
during the creative process and I think
I lost about like 14 pounds in a month
and a half because I was just under
eating and really busy on the computer
but the good thing is that on this
lifestyle I find I can very easily put
on weight and easily put off weight and
for the most part when I'm not really
really busy and kind of distracted with
certain things
feel like I I find uh my way is really
easily stable you know like I usually
sit at 185 but uh yeah I'm a little
lighter than that right now yep got the
cilantro action going on in here
all the herbs and
yeah oh the last thing is the the what's
it called um the
uh sesame seeds yeah wow look at how
seriously look how beautiful that is
that's amazing yeah it's the rainbow
guys
the comments guys helium is amazing with
fruits juices veggies I completely agree
yeah five years plant-based that's
amazing yeah definitely don't be afraid
of the veggies guys
it's yeah there's so many amazing
flavors that you can get from veggies
fruits and vegetables guys that's the
way to go that's that's the way to win
absolutely well let's get these uh these
guys on there
oh hello there we go that perfect Asian
Asian garnish perfect oh it looks
amazing oh you're making me hungry oh
perfect love it should I go for it yeah
let's see it let's see do you taste it
dress
foreign
That's Where It's At absolutely
this is awesome yeah that's great yeah
oh hold me for a second I thought
no
the sauce wasn't quite enough
it's perfect it coaches it's like a
legit pad thigh because
I'll admit I've made some pad ties and
my my natural Saucy Behavior spills into
the bowl sometimes and I've been known
to return noodles into soups you know
and I've been accused of not making
authentic Pad Thai
this is much more like an authentic Pad
Thai how it is like a light coating but
the flavor just really comes through and
everything's really matched up awesome
it's really really tasty yeah but
and I love the sauce
machine if my my thing turned into a
soup because you know that's the great
thing about you know raw sauces they're
so amazing and they make you feel so
great that you can just keep pouring
this is really kind of tweaking my mind
a bit because
I don't know what happened here I'll be
honest
but I almost seriously taste like um
like toasted sesame oil and I know that
the sesame seeds aren't toasted
but this combination is I think more
often I've just put the sesame seeds in
the sauce instead of on top and it's
really making the flavor pop a lot more
having them raw foods are that amazing
that's you know kind of where the the
salty kind of comes in with the toasted
sesame seeds with all the you know Asian
spices I swear yeah and you get you get
some edamame in there and some of the
right veggies and it becomes pretty dang
close so it's pretty cool
Russ is awesome thank you so much for um
letting me make your recipe and share it
with everyone here of course yeah
definitely if you guys are watching make
sure to yeah rewind the video when you
posts it later and make it yourself it's
amazing and definitely I get the raw
bundle because we got lots of recipes in
there we got some
stews and soups and curries by Chris we
got you know I got a couple different
pasta recipes in there there's lots of
different recipes you got yeah check out
check out that before it's gone and make
sure to try all these recipes
absolutely thank you so much so where
can people find you
outside of here yeah so again you can
find me at Raw you know underscore vegan
Emma on Instagram
tube as well and Facebook so yeah check
me out I'm always I'm always on there so
DM me questions you have about raw food
um I love connecting with people and
other other people that are into health
and fitness and yeah definitely
definitely check everything out check
out my website I got lots of free you
know resources on there to check out and
Yeah and obviously check out all of
Chris's amazing recipes he's he's the
raw food Keen he's been doing this for
years so please look up to him for all
the raw food tips
appreciate that we all we all come
together and share and grow together
that's the beautiful thing about this
this bundle to me is
the community right the community and
growing it up making
planting more seeds and getting this
freshness out there because like I said
before it's just so important and you
know when you when you feel the changes
yourself you just really want to share
it right so I just want to thank you
again for for being a part for sharing
on uh on the bundling here tonight and
sharing your recipe is there anything
you want to be us with no thank you so
much that was a great recipe thank you
so much for letting me be a part of it
and I'm so excited for all of you guys
that are watching to try out more
recipes and keep entertaining yourself
and yeah thank you so much thank you
thanks everyone for joining us see you
guys again yeah
bye-bye
foreign